[Music]
Hello, my name is Glinchi, I am a
health insurance advisor, my hometown
is Thrissur. Today's video is completely
different. Today is a comparison
study. We know that there are
many health insurance companies in India. So for
today's video,
we have taken the products of four health insurance
companies.
One is Star
Health's Comprehensive of five
lakhs, Tata's Medicare of Nivpi, as well as
HDC's Optimus Secure. So, today's video is a comparison of four
companies with a premium of five lakhs.
So, if you are trying to
get a good health insurance,
try to watch the entire video without skipping this video.
One of the factors that we consider for the first time is the room
rent. If you
look at Star Health's Comprehensive policy of five lakhs,
we can use a single private room,
as well as
Tata's Medicare.  If it is in Premier Five Lak, it
is Any Room, similarly
in Nibupa, it is Any Room for Five Lak and in Re-Assure
Five Lak, if we look at the case of HDC Optimus Security,
we can use a single private ice room for Five Lak.
In terms of room rent restrictions,
as a personal, I
feel that it is always better to choose Any
Room. To
tell you the reason,
a few days ago, I happened to go to a hospital in Ernakulam
for a friend's chemotherapy. When we went
there,
we usually said that we wanted a normal room, but at that time
they said that there was a vacancy in the deluxe room and
we had to take that deluxe room for that one day. So if we
take Any Room, let us
know that most people have
health insurance. So if we
take Any Room, it is a little better
or if we
go to a room with restrictions, we have to pay extra co-
payment.  There is a chance of coming,
so if
we consider this room rent, let's try to choose the room. Always the
second factor that we should consider is the
restoration. If we say restoration, let's say that a
policy
is a policy of five lakhs. So even if
we use this five lakhs policy,
we will get that ₹5 lakhs again.
That is what is
meant by restoration. So
in terms of restoration, if we look at Star
Health and Tatage as well as
HDFC Optimus Secure, if
we
have taken a policy of five lakhs,
again we get restoration for the same illness and different illness.
But in this case, if you are a
restorer of Bupa, it is very
different. What is special here? If we say that we get
unlimited restoration,
that is, five out of five families.
Imagine that there are five people in a family. So each of these five
people gets this five lakhs
unlimited restoration in
Nipa Bupa.  In
a product called Nibupa's Reassure,
Nibupa's Reassure is a little more attractive in this
regard. Similarly, the third
feature that we can consider is the
pre and post
hospitalization, which is its duration.
That is, if we give an example now,
we are
diagnosing cancer in the hospital.
So before we diagnose, the
doctor will
take some tests, such as MRI,
PET CT, etc., and some of them are
taken before we start the admission to the hospital. Similarly, after the chemotherapy
treatment in the hospital is
over, we are told that
you should
come back for a checkup after six months.
So that is what this pre post means.
The treatment before the hospital and the
treatment after that is a
duration. So what is meant is that it is always
better to take a little more. If we
look at Star Health, the
pre post comes as 60, that is,
before the hospital.  We get 60-day
bills and
90-day bills that have been discharged in
Tata and Star. This is the same
1690.
But in Niva Bupa's Reaser and
Optimus Secur, we can submit bills up to 16180,
which means we can submit bills up to
six months after being discharged from the hospital.
That is a great
feature.
I think that 16180 is a good feature.
This is not only in these two companies, but in
Aadi and Manipal
Cigna, we get this 16 180.
We can submit bills for six months.
Similarly,
the fifth is the no-claim bonus. No-
claim bonus means that if we do not make
any claim, we will
get a policy of five lakhs now. What
I have seen in Star and Tata is that if
we take a policy of five lakhs, after two years,
50% is deposited every year.
After two years, we get
a 10 lakhs bonus, but if a
claim comes, we do not get this no
claim bonus,
as the name suggests. But in this
case, if we add
a safe guard called NCB Protector,
a rider, we can add it. So, if we add
its benefits, if a
claim of up to 50,000
comes, our no claim bonus will
not be lost. That
is a very attractive feature because
often we just make a small claim
or sometimes
we hesitate because we think that we are losing our no claim
bonus. But since
NCB has an NCB
Protector in Niwoopa, this
is a very attractive feature. If it
comes to HDUC, here they give it as a no claim bonus and an
accumulated bonus.
Here, if a claim comes, whether it comes or not, it
becomes double for us,
which is a big five lakhs.  The policy is doubled for
us and doubled by 50%,
so that
is a very attractive feature. And not only that, in Optimus
Secure, we
get coverage from day one to day two, that is,
after taking a policy of five lakhs,
we can use policies up to 10 lakhs.
That is
a special feature of HDFC Optimus Secure only.
And similarly, the next feature that
we can consider is the
coverage of consumables. We know that
after we are admitted to the hospital, we are charged a small expense from our hand, such as
cotton, syringe, non-medical
expense, etc., at the
hospital. So if we
look at this, our Star
Health does not cover this feature,
consumables are not covered in it.
Comprehensive, but in Tata AG,
Bupa, and NetDis, we also
get consumer full expense coverage. That is a very attractive
feature. We always look at it.  Another
feature to consider
is the existing illness waiting
period. We know that
many people often get
rejected by the insurance company after taking a policy because they are not
aware of the waiting period.
So if we look at this, the
waiting period in Star Health is three years for
existing
illnesses and two years for special diseases such as piles, kidney stones.
But if we consider one of their
advantages,
we can reduce this 36 months to three years and one year for one year. If we
pay an extra amount, we get a
feature in the waiting period. In
Star Health, we get a comprehensive waiting period. In
Tata, we get two years for
special diseases and diseases. In the
other two
companies and in Nivaboop, the waiting period is H.  In
DFS, the
waiting period for special diseases is two to three years.
Currently, if we
have sugar or cholesterol, the
waiting period for diseases related to that is three years.
Similarly,
one thing we should pay attention to is that a few days
ago, I received a claim. A
customer was diagnosed with cancer and since it was the
first stage, the
doctor suggested that he
remove that part.
So after
looking at all these insurance companies,
I realized that
most insurance
companies have mentioned a waiting period of two years,
that is, if we remove diseases like Tumor Assist, we have a waiting
period of two years.
So when we take the policy,
try to understand that. Similarly,
maternity coverage is maternity
coverage. If we look at Star
Health's comprehensive, after two
years, we can  If it is normal, it is
15000, if it is caesarean, it is
up to 20000. If we
take a policy of five lakhs, we have to
take the policy and complete two years. If it is
in Tata, after
four years of taking the policy, if a
girl is born, it is 60000 rupees and if it is a
boy, it is 50000 rupees.
I feel that it is a little more in Tata. The
rest is not covered in HDUC and Nibupa
maternity plans. The
same is true when we
say alternative medicine,
that is, we mean
Ayush treatments like Siddha. If we
look at Star Health, we get
maximum cover if it is a
policy of five lakhs, but it is
less than 15000 for us. This is something that
I feel is negative.
In Star, but in the other three
companies, full expenses are also covered and
we get 100% coverage. For
treatments like Ayush, then similarly,
free health checkup is in the
case of health checkup, if it is in
comprehensive, we get every
free  If it is a claim year, that is, if we
have taken a clay policy and
have not made any claim, we can get a health checkup for ₹2000 in the year. If we are in
Tata's Medicare
Plus or Medicare Premier, it is an
irrespective of claim. If we
are taking a policy for five lakhs, we get up to ₹5000 for medical
checkup, whether the claim is received or not.
This is the case in Niwapa and HDC.
We get ₹2500 there, and there is an
irrespective of claim.
Similarly, the next very
interesting element is the
normality of OPD treatment.
Often, people who call from the Gulf
ask about it. OPD
treatment is covered in the Gulf.
We don't need to know anything. Just
go to the doctor and
consult, and we will
get the treatment expense, but that is not the case in
India. We don't get that OPD
like in the Gulf, but even if we don't get it in
this Star's comprehensive.
We get ₹1200 as OPD and per
OPD we get
₹1200.
Similarly, if we are in Tata,
after two years of taking the policy, we get ₹5000 as OPD. The rest of the
OPD coverage is not
available in Niwab Uppa and HDVC. Similarly,
normal insurance companies do not give it to us for
dental treatments,
but in comprehensive, they
give us ₹5000 every three years.
But in this case,
what is the benefit if we are in Tata's Medical Plus? After two
years of taking both the policies, we are
given up to ₹10000 as treatment expenses every year.
So that is a very attractive
feature. Next,
claim settlement is something that many people
ask about. How is the settlement process? The
claim settlement
ratio of these four companies is above 90 percent.
And not only that, if we
look at our annual report of IRD,
we can see that the claim settlement ratio is
We get the claim incurred ratio, which is a detail of how much the company has paid in claim amount. So if we look at the annual
report on page 173,
we can know how much it is. No
company is bad. Not every company
can reject a claim without a reason. So when we are
worried, which company is good for many people
depends on many factors. One thing is for
sure. No insurance
company
can reject a claim without a reason. Sometimes,
we may not know the waiting period.
So often what
happens to us is the same. If we
take the case of hospital network, if we take the
case of hospital network,
Star Health and HDFC have the most network. They
get hospital network coverage above 10,000. But it is not that there is
no coverage in the rest of the Tata and the department. There is also a
network above 8,000.
So you check it. Check whether the company you are
going to is covered.  Let's try to do it. The
last thing I want to say is that every
company is unique. Each company has its own
unique
features. So, try to understand your features and your needs before taking a
policy. If
you have any doubts about any policies, or if you are
interested in taking a policy, you can contact me.
Thank you, greetings, dear ones. If you
like the videos of Katukumani, you should join us.